A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Projects, Series L FA348
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Magazines - "Nation's Heritage", 1948 (Box 111, Folder 1077)
  Brochure. NAR will be a charter subscriber. Correspondents include Malcolm Forbes.
- Magazines - "Newsweek" - Correspondence - Stock Subscription, 1932-1936 (Box 111, Folder 1078)
  NAR subscribed to stock of new magazine. Tenant in Rockefeller Center. NAR took no management interest in magazine.
- Magazines - "Newsweek" - "Nelson Rockefeller Southward Ho", 1948 (Box 111, Folder 1079)
  Cover story on NAR. News Bulletin on Article from Venezuela. Congratulations to NAR and requests for aid resulting from article.
- Magazines - "Of Westchester", 1969-1971 (Box 111, Folder 1080)
  Correspondence re articles and Clippings. Copy of "Transcript of extemporaneous Illustrated Art Lecture", 3/15/67.
- Magazines - "Reader's Digest", 1947-1969 (Box 111, Folder 1081)
  Correspondence re article on IBEC (International Basic Economy Corporation) in Brazil. Other articles on Latin America. Reprints of articles. Complimentary membership in Condensed Book Club, 1953. Requests for interviews, articles and information.
- Magazines - "The Reporter", 1949-1959 (Box 112, Folder 1082)
  Correspondence re subscriptions; the 10th anniversary issue; reprints of articles; requests for opinions; correspondence with Max Ascoli.
- Magazines - "Saturday Evening Post", 1951 (Box 112, Folder 1083)
  "The Rockefellers - The Story of 5 Young Millionaires." Comments and requests resulting from article.
- Magazines - "Scholastic" - John W. Studebaker, 1948-1961 (Box 112, Folder 1084)
  Copies of "Jr. Scholastic" with articles on Latin America. NAR Brotherhood Statement and drafts. Various articles sent. Grace Bennish painting. Correspondents include John W. Studebaker, Herbert Marx.
- Magazines - "Theater Arts", 1948-1958 (Box 112, Folder 1085)
  Appeals for aid declined. Request for interview declined.
- Magazines - "This Week", 1948-1967 (Box 112, Folder 1086)
  Correspondence re article on IBEC (International Basic Economy Corporation). Articles sent for NAR's comment. Article by NAR, 1966. Article on Rockefeller family, 1967. Requests for article.
- Magazines - "Time", 1945-1971 (Box 112, Folder 1087)
  Correspondence re NAR participation in "Time" Radio Broadcast 1945. Article on IBEC, 1948. Articles sent to NAR for information. Art work; clippings; letter of introduction for Frank Norris; requests for information; invitations to receptions; 1963 statement of income.
- Magazines - "United Nations World" - Michael Straight & Louis Dolivet, 1946-1951 (Box 112, Folder 1088)
  "A Project for Publishing an International Weekly on the UN and World Affairs." NAR interest and support. Origins and founding of the Periodical. Clippings. David Rockefeller article on International House.
- Magazines - "U.S. News & World Report", 1947-1962 (Box 112, Folder 1089)
  Correspondence re advertising articles sent for NAR's information. Subscription, merger of "U.S. News" and "World Report," interview with NAR, 1949, photograph, 1951.
- Magazines - "Vision", 1949-1950 (Box 112, Folder 1090)
  New magazine for Latin America. Attempts to interest NAR; declined. First issue and NAR's response. Correspondents include Noel May, William Barton.
- Magner, A. K. Jr., Ken & Jeanadele - Broadcasters, 1950-1968 (Box 112, Folder 1091)
  Correspondence re surgery for Jeanadele Shimler Magner. John Davison Rockefeller Jr. letter to NAR. Offers to work for NAR declined. Copy of article by Mr. & Mrs. Magner.
- Maine, State of, Mt. Desert Isle, Seal Harbor, etc. - General, 1967-1971 (Box 112, Folder 1092)
  Appeals for financial aid. Letters requesting NAR exert his influence for certain causes and against the proposed Trenton Industrial Park. Invitation from Gov. Curtis to serve on National Governors' Advisory Committee declined.
- Malaria - Dr. Fred L. Soper, 1946-1951 (Box 113, Folder 1093)
  Correspondence. Appointment with NAR. Dr. Soper's receipt of the Lasker Award. Director of RF IHD. Plans to eliminate and control malaria.
- Managerial Group for European Reconstruction, 1947 (Box 113, Folder 1094)
  Frank A. Lindsay's "Organization of a Managerial Group for European Reconstruction." Outline of his economic recovery plans. C.B.F. Brill's interview with Lindsay.
- Magnum, Robert, 1957-1958 (Box 113, Folder 1095)
  Victor Borella memos. Brilliant Negro Police Commissioner interviewed by Borella for possible position. Resume, clippings re his accident.
- Mansfield, Richard H., 1947-1958 (Box 113, Folder 1096)
  NAR congratulations on new job. Clippings. Partner with Mansfield and Edward G. Miller, Jr. IBEC stock.
- Mark, Dr. Julius - Rabbi, Temple Emanu-El, 1969-1970 (Box 113, Folder 1097)
  Citation received by Rabbi Mark. Correspondence re preparation and wording of the citation.
- Marshall Plan - General, 1947 (Box 113, Folder 1098)
  NAR sends copies of his outline, "United States Participation in the Rehabilitation of Europe," to William Aldrich, Ruml, J.J. McCloy, etc. Jones-Stein Memorandum reacting to NAR. Stacy May comments on NAR outline. Correspondents include Mrs. John Davison Rockefeller 3rd.
- Marshall Plan - Clippings, 1947 (Box 113, Folder 1099)
  Newspaper clippings and magazines.
- Marshall Plan - Committee for Economic Development - Reports, 1947-1948 (Box 113, Folder 1100)
  Printed Copies.
- Marshall Plan - Correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 113, Folder 1101)
  NAR Membership Program and NAR suggestions. Draft of policy statements. "An American Program for European Economic Cooperation." Correspondents include Wayne Taylor, Gardner Means, Arthur Vandenburg, Stacy May.
- Marshall Plan - Printed Material, 1947-1949 (Box 113, Folder 1102A)
  "How To Do Business Under The Marshall Plan" by E. K. Gubrey. "Dollars Can Help Save Europe." Other literature. Various statements. "Report of the ECA Commerce Mission."
- Marshall Plan - Printed Material, 1947-1949 (Box 113, Folder 1102B)
- Marshall Plan - Council on Foreign Relations, 1947-1948 (Box 113, Folder 1103)
  Digests of Meetings. Invitations to meetings.
- Marshall Plan - Committee for Printed Matter, 1947-1948 (Box 114, Folder 1104)
  "Recovery in Europe." "The Problem of Closing Europe's Dollar Gap." List of members of the Committee for the Marshall Plan.
- Marshall Plan - National Committee for the Marshall Plan, 1947-1948 (Box 114, Folder 1105)
  "Recovery in Europe, The First Two Years of Marshall Aid." Invitations. Thanks NAR for support. Correspondents include Paul G. Hoffman.
- Mathais, Herbert J., 1947-1957 (Box 114, Folder 1106)
  Stock analyst would like position. Crank letters revealing his racial prejudices. Correspondents include R. H. Mansfield.
- Maxwell, Russell L., 1946-1951 (Box 114, Folder 1107)
  NAR's congratulations when he joins American Machine and Foundry Corp. Introduces Dr. Brunn. NAR requests two of Maxwell's speeches.
- May, Stacy - General, 1948-1960 (Box 114, Folder 1108)
  Correspondence between NAR and Stacy May re projects, trips, studies, reports on activities.
- May, Stacy, 1960 (Box 114, Folder 1109)
  Correspondence re Tarrytown African Festival. Mrs. Nelson (Mary Clark Rockefeller) notes.
- May, Stacy - Speeches, 1951-1954 (Box 114, Folder 1110)
  Copies of 1954 Speech at World Population Conference and Denver Social Science Conference and relative correspondence.
- May, Stacy - Speeches - Boston Conference on Distribution, 1951 (Box 114, Folder 1111)
- McCabe, Thomas B., 1944-1958 (Box 114, Folder 1112)
  Luncheon accepted by NAR. NAR congratulates him on his new position as President of Scott Paper. Mexico's conditions.
- McCarthy, Frank, 1945-1961 (Box 114, Folder 1113)
  Personal letter. Sorry to miss NAR in Williamsburg. Thanks for NAR contribution to George C. Marshall Research Foundation.
- McClintock, John - United Fruit Company, 1941-1961 (Box 114, Folder 1114)
  Correspondence re buying equipment and refinery, projects, magazine article, appointments, reports, activities, trips, and jobs.
- McCloy, John J., 1945-1949 (Box 114, Folder 1115)
  NAR introduction to Thomas Armstrong, Jones, Milbank, Tweed and Hope. Hadley's and McCloy's personal notes. NAR congratulations.
- McCloy, John J. - Godkin Lectures: Challenge to American Foreign Policy, 1953 (Box 114, Folder 1116)
  Lectures sent to NAR, which John J. McCloy gave at Harvard.
- McCollum, Leonard F., 1946-1951 (Box 115, Folder 1117)
  NAR advice as to whether he should join Board of Institute of International Educators. "Management's Frontier." Correspondents include Larry Duggan.
- McCoy, Georgia France, Mrs., 1958-1969 (Box 115, Folder 1118)
  Correspondence re gifts sent to NAR from India. Appointment to see NAR. Job Applications. OFfer of Indian Art sale declined.
- McCracken, Dr. Robert J., 1948-1967 (Box 115, Folder 1119)
  Correspondence re sermons. Pastor at Riverside Church. McCracken's declination to serve on "Elect NAR" committee. McCracken's resignation.
- McCrary, Mr. and Mrs. John R. (Tex & Jinx), 1946-1958 (Box 115, Folder 1120)
  Tex's radio program, personal notes. Tex's advice on NAR speech. Tex's PR course. His letter to Eisenhower.
- McGrath, Alfred F. (Dartmouth Classmate), 1947-1967 (Box 115, Folder 1121)
  Correspondence re Mr. McGrath's use of NAR as reference. Christmas greetings; postal cards; obituaries - 1/16/67.
- McGraw-Hill Corporation - McGraw Hill International Corporation, 1945-1957 (Box 115, Folder 1122)
  Clipping. Spanish language technical publication. Management Digest tearsheet. "IBEC Seeks New Worlds." Courtesy card for NAR. Correspondents include Howard Knowles, Paul Miller.
- Medicine - Medical Associations, 1958-1971 (Box 115, Folder 1123)
  Project reports; studies of medical problems; appeals of aid; information on pharmaceuticals; proposals; requests for information. Most correspondence prior to 1958 discarded.
- Medicine - Medical Associations - Medicine - Chiropractics, 1970 (Box 115, Folder 1124)
  Correspondence with Dr. Oringer re Bernarr McFadden Fund & chiropractics.
- Memberships - Honorary - Foreign - Offers of, 1958 (Box 115, Folder 1125)
  Correspondence re offers from Mexico and Brazil to join organizations. Both declined.
- Memorials - General Correspondence, 1952-1971 (Box 115, Folder 1126)
  Appeals for contributions to Memorial Funds. Most invitations to participate in Memorial ceremonies and serve on memorial committees declined. NAR sponsored Clinton G. Martin Memorial Park and gave contribution in 1967. Most material previous to 1958 discarded.
- Memorials - Carrie Chapman Catt Memorial Fund, 1948-1956 (Box 115, Folder 1127)
  NAR contributed $1,000. Progress reports.
- Memorials - Churchill Memorials, 1964-1970 (Box 115, Folder 1128)
  Invitation to serve on Committee for Winston S. Churchill Memorial at Westminster College, Fulton, Missouri. NAR contribution to Churchill Memorial Fund, English Speaking Union and Royal Ball, 1965.
- Memorials - John McLane Clark Memorial Fund, Inc., 1951-1958 (Box 115, Folder 1129)
  Correspondence re Memorial Fund in honor of this 1932 Dartmouth graduate. NAR contribution, 1951. NAR loan for printing costs, 1958.
- Memorials - Rockefeller, Laura Spelman Memorial, 1933 (Box 115, Folder 1130)
  Final Report.
- Memorials - William Church Osborn Memorial, 1951 (Box 115, Folder 1131)
  NAR on Committee. Contribution.
- Mental Health - General Correspondence, 1948-1971 (Box 116, Folder 1132)
- Mental Health - Children, Disturbed, Retarded, etc., 1958-1971 (Box 116, Folder 1133)
  NAR contributions to various local chapters and NY State Association in 1966, 1970, and 1971. NAR contribution to Association for Mentally Ill Children of Westchester - 1970.
- Mental Health - Children, Disturbed, Retarded, etc. - Albany & Westchester County Chapters, 1958-1971 (Box 116, Folder 1134)
- Mental Health - Children, Disturbed, Retarded, etc. - Albany & Westchester County Chapters - Albany County Mental Health Association, 1959-1968 (Box 116, Folder 1135)
  Appeals for financial aid; NAR contributions 1959, 1967, 1968.
- Messersmith, George S., 1941-1947 (Box 116, Folder 1136)
  Ambassador to Argentina, "Time" cover story. NAR congratulations on new appointment. 1947 Speech before American Foundation.
- Metropolitan Opera Co., Inc., 1938-1960 (Box 116, Folder 1137)
  Financial report 1938-1939. Report on Municipal Music and Art Center. Appeal for help with scenery. Invitations to Opera Conference declined.
- Metropolitan Police and Police Boys' Club in Washington D.C., 1958-1973 (Box 116, Folder 1138)
  NAR contributions. Controversy over segregated facilities.
- Mexican Interests, 1939-1940 (Box 117, Folder 1139)
  Art and Oil. Comments on Mexican conditions made to NAR. Irving Leonard report on a visit to Mexico. Expropriation of oil in Mexico. SOCONJ (Standard Oil Company of New Jersey) transcript of articles.
- Mexican Interests - Mexico, Pilgrims and Foundation, 1947-1950 (Box 117, Folder 1140)
  Printed Matter. Interest in NAR property. Invitations. Appeals declined. Correspondents include Mr. S. Bolling Wright.
- Meyer, Eugene, 1946-1947 (Box 117, Folder 1141)
  "Washington Post" editor and friend of NAR. NAR praise of Herblock cartoon. NAR praise of speech.
- Miami Foreign Trade Forum, 1947-1948 (Box 117, Folder 1142)
  Greeting by NAR, who cannot be there. Correspondents include Frank Jamieson, Frederick Home.
- Michanowsky, George, 1946-1955 (Box 117, Folder 1143)
  His work with CIO re UN position. Plea for NAR's aid. New job. NAR declines reference.
- Middle East - General, 1950-1958 (Box 117, Folder 1144)
  Three reports to NAR on conditions in Middle East.
- Miles, Mr. & Mrs. Arnold (Alice), Mrs. George Morgenstern, 1954-1970 (Box 117, Folder 1145)
  NAR friendship and assistance to family of Washington, D.C. friend. Collection of copies of Arnold Miles letters. Views of NAR during the 1950's; HEW Washington politics. Worked with Rockefeller Brothers Fund, International Basic Economy Corporation.
- Milligan, Lloyd S., 1955-1956 (Box 117, Folder 1146)
  Wants financial help to study theology. NAR impressed with his address at Pocantico. Asks NAR aid for religious projects. Declined.
- Milton, David - General Correspondence, 1944-1949 (Box 117, Folder 1147)
  David Milton sells NAR a Jeep. Clipping re David Milton from "Daily Worker."
- Mindszenty, Joseph Cardinal, 1949 (Box 117, Folder 1148)
  NAR supports Sol Bloom's action for Cardinal. Marie Brentano article on a trial of Mindszenty.
- Minor, Clark H., 1947 (Box 117, Folder 1149)
  "Commandeur" in French National Order of the Legion of Honor. NAR would like to have lunch with him.
- Minsch, William Jr. - Minsch, Monell & Co., 1947 (Box 117, Folder 1150)
  Sends article, "Story Behind Argentina's Role at Rio." Praises NAR.
- Miss USA Pageant - Caribbean Exposition, 1955-1956 (Box 117, Folder 1151)
  NAR declines table. Expresses interest in the pageant.
- Mizelle, Mrs. Virginia Prewett, 1947-1969 (Box 117, Folder 1152)
  Journalist wrote on Latin American affairs. Friend of NAR. Dr. Sayao's farm colony. NAR interest in a nutritionist in Goiaz. Personal note. Correspondents include Berent Friele.
- Moe, Henry Allen, 1947-1968 (Box 117, Folder 1153)
  NAR personal friendship. Moe given Cosmos Club Award, 1965; copy of his acceptance speech is in file. Speech on Scholarship. Suggestions on future activities of d'Harnoncourt.
- Montevideo, Minnesota Fiesta Days - L. P. Sickles, 1947-1951 (Box 117, Folder 1154)
  Invitations to participate. CIAC. NAR Chairman. Correspondents include Frederick de Coste.
- Moore, Frank C., 1958-1968 (Box 117, Folder 1155)
  Friendship. Association through Government Affairs Foundation.
- Moore, Frank C., 1958-1968 (Box 117, Folder 1156)
  Eugene P. Clarendon visit with NAR. Cargo to Latin America.
- Morhouse, L. Judson, 1955-1957 (Box 117, Folder 1157)
  Re the "Family of Man"; Republican State Committee Dinner. Sends the "Last Hurrah".
- Moses, Robert - General, 1946-1971 (Box 118, Folder 1158)
  United Nations, Urban Traffic, steel process, trip to Latin America, tribute to Robert Moses. State Parks.
- Moses, Robert - Coles, Albert M. Correspondence on Housing, 1955 (Box 118, Folder 1159)
  Discussion of Slum Clearance.
- Moses, Robert - M.R. Marti, Jose Statue, 1954-1955 (Box 118, Folder 1160)
  Statue of Jose Marti planning. Proposal for creating a central mall.
- Motion Picture Association of America, Inc., 1949-1950 (Box 118, Folder 1161)
  Request for appointment with NAR. Joaquin Rickard. Latin American Division.
- Movements for European Unity - General Correspondence, 1948-1952 (Box 118, Folder 1162)
  Memos on International Coordinating Committee. NAR help with Committee. Invitations for NAR to Economic Conference, London. Beardsley Ruml article. Correspondents include I. Beddington-Behrens, Arthur W. Packard, Duncan Sandys.
- Movements for European Unity - Clippings, 1948-1952 (Box 118, Folder 1163)
  Clippings and printed material.
- Mowrer, Edgar Ansel - "Western World" Magazine, 1956-1959 (Box 118, Folder 1164)
  NAR interview and interest in founding of magazine. NAR declines official help. Would like NAR article. Correspondents include Lucien Radoux.
- Mowrer, Edgar Ansel - "Western World" Magazine - NAR Article, 1957 (Box 118, Folder 1165)
  Handwritten notes and drafts
- Mowrer, Edgar Ansel - "Western World" Magazine - "Latin America and the Western World", 1957 (Box 118, Folder 1166)
  Final copy of the article.
- NOT USED (Box 118, Folder 1167)
- Museums - General (A-G), 1947-1971 (Box 119, Folder 1168)
  Appeals for contributions and loans declined.
- Museums - General (H-Z), 1947-1971 (Box 119, Folder 1169)
- Museums - American Armed Forces Museum - Correspondence & Memos, 1956-1960 (Box 119, Folder 1170)
  NAR heads Committee to study possibility of museum. Finances study. Report to ad hoc committee. Appointment of Presidential Commission to study problem. Decision to turn matter over to Smithsonian Institution.
- Museums - American Armed Forces Museum - Proceedings, Printed Matter and Reports, 1956-1959 (Box 119, Folder 1171)
  Studies of museum possibilities.
- Museums - American Armed Forces Museum - Proceedings of Meeting, 1956 (Box 119, Folder 1172)
- Museums - American Association of Museums, 1933-1972 (Box 120, Folder 1173)
  NAR contribution to Association. Correspondents include Mrs. Rodman Clark Rockefeller.
- Museums - American Museum Of Health, 1947-1948 (Box 120, Folder 1174)
  Unsuccessful attempt to interest NAR in museum.
- Museums - American Museum of Natural History, 1946-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1175)
  NAR gift of three Peruvian Mummies in 1946. NAR and Rockefeller Brothers Fund contributions.
- Museums - Boston Museum of Fine Arts, 1969-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1176)
  NAR a member for centennial year only.
- Museums - Brooklyn Museum, 1951-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1177)
  Summary of Rockefeller family gifts to Museum as of 1953. NAR gifts to museum. NAR loans items for exhibit, 1962.
- Museums - Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington D.C., 1950-1960 (Box 120, Folder 1178)
  Requests for loans of NAR art; 1950 granted. 1961 declined.
- Museums - Dallas Museum of Fine Arts, 1956-1959 (Box 120, Folder 1179)
  Unsuccessful efforts to interest NAR in work of museum.
- Museums - Downtown Museum of the City of New York, 1967 (Box 120, Folder 1180)
  Drawings, diagrams, maps, models and budget summary for 1967.
- Museums - Guggenheim Museum, NAR Member of Associates, 1952-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1181)
  Printed material; correspondence re opening, special events and exhibits; payment of membership dues; invitation to NAR to become an associate; press releases on events.
- Museums - Hammond Museum, North Salem, NY, 1966-1970 (Box 120, Folder 1182)
  Invitations; appeals for aid; financial reports; petition to NAR to help find funds for museum in 1969; memos re financial state of Museum.
- Museums - Heckscher Museum, Huntington, L.I., 1964-1971 (Box 120, Folder 1183)
  Annual reports, 1967, 1969. NAR contributions 1964-1969, 1971.
- Museums - Hudson River Museum, Yonkers, N.Y., 1969-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1184)
  Invitations; request for loan of African Art; releases; NAR declined membership.
- Museums - Israel Museum in Jerusalem, 1969-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1185)
  Printed material. NAR contributions through the America-Israel Cultural Foundation, 1969, 1970, 1971.
- Museums - Jekyll Island Museum, 1958-1970 (Box 121, Folder 1186)
  Requests for information on the "Rockefeller Museum" on Jekyll Island and comments on its disrepair. Invitation to visit the Museum declined.
- Museums - Joseph H. Hirshorn Museum & Sculptural Garden, 1965-1969 (Box 121, Folder 1187)
  Clippings; correspondence re locating museum in Washington, D.C. rather than Westchester County, NY. Invitation to NAR to be Trustee declined.
- Museums - Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1961-1967 (Box 121, Folder 1188)
  Correspondence re NAR lending pieces of art for exhibitions; selling a Henry Moore sculpture; NAR donation of a wood block to art auction, 1961; NAR contribution for cataloguing an exhibition.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - General, 1932-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1189)
  Press releases and printed material; invitations declined; correspondence re expansion, loans, activities, finances, appointments, invitations, exhibitions, primitive art collection transfer. NAR contributions, 1965, 1967, 1968, 1971.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Charter, Constitution, By-Laws, 1947-1969 (Box 121, Folder 1190)
  Copies of these items. Correspondence re revision.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Clipping & Press Releases, 1948-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1191)
  Clippings, 1948-1871, and releases, 1968, re events and activities.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Financial Statements, 1965-1968 (Box 121, Folder 1192)
  As submitted to the Board.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - One-Hundredth Anniversary, 1969-1970 (Box 121, Folder 1193)
  NAR a Centennial Sponsor.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Priest, Alan R., 1963 (Box 121, Folder 1194)
  Correspondence re his retirement, salary, and retirement benefits.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Primitive Art, Department of, 1969-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1195)
  Correspondence re the collection, agreement on transfer of collection, the Visiting Committee, 1969-1971.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - Trustees, 1952-1971 (Box 121, Folder 1196)
  Lists of Trustees and Addresses; committees; minutes of meetings; correspondence re issues before the Board 1952-1971.
- Museums - Metropolitan Museum of Art - NAR's Resignation Board of Trustees, 1946-1951 (Box 121, Folder 1197)
  Correspondence re resignation and election as Honorary Trustee.
- Museums - Museum of African Art, Washington D.C., 1965-1970 (Box 122, Folder 1198)
  Clippings; invitation to opening; correspondence re possibility of a Museum of Primitive Art Exhibit in Washington D.C.
- Museums - Museum of Art, San Juan, P.R. & Institute of Puerto Rican Culture, 1958-1959 (Box 122, Folder 1199)
  Correspondence re NAR's loan of paintings to the Institute for exhibit. Photos, condition reports on several of the paintings, reports on restoration work done and shipping procedures. Clippings.
- Museums - Museum of Contemporary Crafts of American Craftsmen's Council, 1956-1970 (Box 122, Folder 1200)
  Clipping on opening, 1956. NAR contributions, 1963-1967, 1970. NAR served as sponsor for benefit, 1968.
- Museums - Museum of Modern Art (MoMA) - General, 1935-1938 (Box 122, Folder 1201)